<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Francisco Rodriguez</title><link>https://franciscorodriguez92.github.io/authors/admin/</link><atom:link href="https://franciscorodriguez92.github.io/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Francisco Rodriguez</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2025 Francisco Rodríguez</copyright><image><url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url><title>Francisco Rodriguez</title><link>https://franciscorodriguez92.github.io/authors/admin/</link></image><item><title>Francisco Rodriguez</title><link>https://franciscorodriguez92.github.io/authors/admin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://franciscorodriguez92.github.io/authors/admin/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="about-me"&gt;About Me&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m a senior data scientist and NLP/LLM researcher based in Valais, Switzerland. Over the past nine years, I’ve worked at the intersection of academia and industry, building machine learning systems end to end. My main focus is on large language models — from data preparation and fine-tuning to evaluation and deployment in production. Along the way, I’ve worked on retrieval-augmented generation, predictive analytics, and customer intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-i-do-best"&gt;What I do best&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NLP &amp;amp; LLMs&lt;/strong&gt;: adapting models to specific domains, evaluating systems, and exploring safety and bias&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Production ML&lt;/strong&gt;: building reliable data pipelines, setting up CI/CD for models, feature stores, monitoring, and A/B testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analytics that drive impact&lt;/strong&gt;: translating raw feedback, support tickets, or chats into clear insights and decisions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="current-work"&gt;Current work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;strong&gt;Hilti AG&lt;/strong&gt;, I focus on customer feedback intelligence, retention modeling, and building scalable ML pipelines that power analytics and operational tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also collaborate with &lt;strong&gt;UNED’s NLP group&lt;/strong&gt; on projects around bias mitigation, multilingual sexism detection, and LLM fine-tuning. I co-led the &lt;strong&gt;EXIST shared task&lt;/strong&gt; and created the &lt;strong&gt;MeTwo&lt;/strong&gt; dataset.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>